Register of the Petr Berngardovich Struve papers, 1890-1987
Hoover Institution Archives
- FILES CREATED AS EDITOR AND CONTRIBUTOR, 1914-1934 (Boxes 24-37)
  - Vozrozhdenie (Paris), 1917-1928
    - Articles submitted for publication
      - Plaksin, Boris, holograph
        - "Iz nedavnego proshlogo" (Box-folder 35: 60)
        - "K voprosu o vozrashchenii na rodinu" (Box-folder 35: 61)
      - Pletnev, Aleksei, "Budushchee Rossii," holograph (Box-folder 35: 62)
      - Pogodin, A. L., typescripts
        - "Vozvrashchenie Dmovskogo k politicheskoi zhizni" (Box-folder 35: 63)
        - "Zavety shestidesiatykh godov" (Box-folder 35: 64)
      - "Politik," "Na perelome," typescript (Box-folder 35: 65)
      - Polunin, A. P., speech at the V. V. Vorovskii murder court hearing, holograph, 1923 November (Box-folder 35: 66)
      - Popov, Aleksandr, "Pis'mo iz Podkarpatskoi Rusi. Chekhizatsiia cherez ukrainizatsiiu. Goneniia na russkuiu emigratsiiu," holograph (Box-folder 35: 67)
      - Potugin, A., "Nansenovskoe bedstvie - pis'mo iz Sofii," holograph (Box-folder 35: 68)
      - Pskovskii Otdel Vserossiiskogo Narodnogo Soiuza, "Vsem Russkim! Vsem Slavianam!," holograph (Box-folder 35: 69)
      - Radkovskii, A., "Sakko i Vanzetti," holograph (Box-folder 35: 70)
      - Ramenskii, Mikhail, "Dumy emigranta," holograph (Box-folder 35: 71)
      - Rennikov (Selitrennikov), A.
        - "Malen'kii fel'eton - politicheskie vunderkindy," typescript (Box-folder 35: 72)
        - "Otkrytoe pis'mo Klare Tsetkinoi," galley proof (Box-folder 35: 73)
        - "Podlinnoe litso," galley proof (Box-folder 35: 74)
      - Rodionov, V., "Bozhe Spasi Rossiiu," holograph (Box-folder 35: 75)
      - Rozanov, S. N., "O s'ezde," holograph (Box-folder 35: 76)
      - Rozen-Meier, N., translation of "Draguny de Zhanze," holograph (Box-folder 35: 77)
      - Rozenshil'd-Paulin, A., "Golos ottuda," holograph (Box-folder 35: 78)
      - "Russian immigrant," "Otvet Dem'ianu Bednomu," poem, holograph (Box-folder 35: 79)
      - Russpress
        - "Politicheskii Biulleten," No. 2039, typescript, 1927 September 9 (Box-folder 35: 80)
        - "Russkii s'ezd vo L'vove," typescript (Box-folder 35: 81)
      - Rynda, Nikola, "Syny Rossi," typescript (Box-folder 35: 82)
      - Sablin, E. V., letters from London, 1927 January-August (Box-folder 35: 83)
      - Sadovskii, Iakov D.
        - "Razgovor na malorusskom narechii," holograph (Box-folder 36: 1)
        - "S fronta domoi - iz vospominanii goda," typescript, 1918 (Box-folder 36: 2)
      - Salivanov, N., obituary of A. N. Ventsel', holograph, 1927 March 3 (Box-folder 36: 3)
      - Saltykov, Aleksandr, "Rezul'taty agrarnoi revoliutsii," holograph (Box-folder 36: 4)
      - Semenov, Iu.
        - "K telegrammam," holograph (Box-folder 36: 5)
        - Untitled typescript (Box-folder 36: 6)
      - Semenov-Tian'-Shanskii, V. P., conversation with a person from Petrograd, holograph (Box-folder 36: 7)
      - Shabovich, Iulian, "Moi perepiski: nuzhno podrazhat' predkam," holograph (Box-folder 36: 8)
      - Shakhovskoi, D. A., "Pis'mo O. Sharliu Kene," holograph (Box-folder 36: 9)
      - Shapovalenko, N., "Vernye dolgu," typescript (Box-folder 36: 10)
      - Shcherbachev, B., "Vybory v Nitstse," holograph (Box-folder 36: 11)
      - Shipovskii, Mikhail, "Russkii lager' v Viunsdorfe," holograph (Box-folder 36: 12)
      - Shorets, Gerasim, "Podrobnosti muchenicheskoi smerti Episkopa Tobol'skogo Germogena Dolganova," holograph (Box-folder 36: 13)
      - Silevich, "Latviisko-Sovetskii dogovor i Anglo-Sovetskii razryv," holograph (Box-folder 36: 14)
      - Sineokov, I., "Otkrytoe pis'mo Generalu Bogaevskomu," holograph (Box-folder 36: 15)
      - Smolenskii, G. and others, paper on E. N. Chirikov's novel Zver' iz bezdny, holograph, 1927 February 24 (Box-folder 36: 16)
      - Soiuz Russkikh Ofitserov v Korolevstve Vengrii, resolution, typescript (Box-folder 36: 17)
      - Sole..., "O Tseliakh, sredstvakh, i vozmozhnostiakh," typescript (Box-folder 36: 18)
      - Solovei Budmirovich (V. L. Bogdanovich), "K poznaniiu ..." (Box-folder 36: 19)
      - Solov'eva, Sestra, untitled paper on General Kornilov, typescript (Box-folder 36: 20)
      - Spadrin, A. (A. Spasskii), "Belgradskaia 'tekhnospomoshch'," holograph (Box-folder 36: 21)
      - Spasskii, A. A. (Spadrin), "Russkoe gore," typescript (Box-folder 36: 22)
      - Stomma, Vitol'd, "25-oe noiabria v Mikhailovskom Artilleriiskom Uchilishche," holograph (Box-folder 36: 23)
      - Stroev, V. N.
        - Biographical essay on P. M. Stroev, typescript (Box-folder 36: 24)
        - "Prichiny neudachi tak nazyvaemago Russkago Nauchnago Instituta v Berline," holograph (Box-folder 36: 25)
      - Struve, K., "Ispytanie tserkovnogo edinstva v zarubezhnoi Rossii," holograph (Box-folder 36: 26)
      - Struve, L., holograph
        - "Kalinin" (Box-folder 36: 27)
        - "Obyski u intelligentsii i sovetskikh sluzhashchikh" (Box-folder 36: 28)
      - Sungarin, "Kitaiskie dela. Marshal Chan Tszolin - verkhovnyi pravitel," holograph (Box-folder 36: 29)
      - Svetlik, P., "Razgovory o zarubezhnom s'ezde," holograph (Box-folder 36: 30)
      - Taube (Anichkova), S. I., "K.P. Kramarzhu--neutomimomu bortsu s bol'shevizmom," typescript (Box-folder 36: 31)
      - Temnikov, Leonti, "Zapiska chitannaia 30-IX-26 v Russkom Ob'edinenii v Prage," holograph (Box-folder 36: 32)
      - Terskii, A., "Polozhenie krest'ianskogo khoziaistva v Sibiri," typescript (Box-folder 36: 33)
      - Tikhmenev, Boris, "Staryi i novyi stil'," holograph (Box-folder 36: 34)
      - Titov, F., "K zakatu 'zarubezhnogo s'ezda'," holograph (Box-folder 36: 35)
      - Tolstaia, E. N., letter to P. B. Struve and poem "Les Fleurs du Nord," typescript, 1927 January 25 (Box-folder 36: 36)
      - Trakhterev, O. S., "Mozhno, no inache...," holograph (Box-folder 36: 37)
      - Truba, Ivan, "Otkrytoe pis'mo rektoru Ukrainskoi privatnoi akademii v ChSR," holograph (Box-folder 36: 38)
      - Trubetskoi, Prince Grigorii N., untitled paper on Russian unity, holograph (Box-folder 36: 39)
      - Trzhesetskii, A., "Problema schast'ia i bor'ba za sushchestvovanie," holograph (Box-folder 36: 40)
      - Tsekh, Dmitrii, "Uroki zarubezhnogo s'ezda" (Box-folder 36: 41)
      - Tsurikov, N. A., holographs
        - "Assenizatsiia emigratsii" (Box-folder 36: 42)
        - "Bezvestnye' geroi i 'zasluzhennyi' deiatel'" (Box-folder 36: 43)
        - "Dlia urazumeniia" (Box-folder 36: 44)
        - "Geroizm" (Box-folder 36: 45)
        - "Mimokhodom" (Box-folder 36: 46)
        - "Nezabyaemoe proshloe i obiazatel'noe nastoiashchee" (Box-folder 36: 47)
        - "O 'zveriakh' i o 'bezdne'" (Box-folder 36: 48)
        - "Ostanovites'" (Box-folder 36: 49)
        - "Pora poniat'" (Box-folder 36: 50)
        - "Proshchaite," concerning the speech of A. A. Pilenko (Box-folder 36: 51)
        - "Vynuzhdennyi otvet" (Box-folder 36: 52)
      - Tsytovich, Evgenii V., "K voprosu chistoy russkogo iazyka," holograph (Box-folder 36: 53)
      - Tuberozov, A., "Uniatskaia propaganda," typescript (Box-folder 36: 54)
      - Turtsovich, N. L., "Eshche o zarubezhnom s'ezde," typescript (Box-folder 36: 55)
      - Tuz, "Sredi grenel'skikh molodtsov," holograph (Box-folder 36: 56)
      - Urvantsov, Lev, "My," holograph (Box-folder 36: 57)
      - Varshavskii, S.
        - "Delo sovetskikh shpionov," holograph (Box-folder 36: 58)
        - "Evraziitsy i esery," holograph (Box-folder 36: 59)
        - "Gde bol'she voruiut?," holograph (Box-folder 36: 60)
        - "K perekhodu A. V. Peshekhonova na sovetskuiu sluzhby," holograph (Box-folder 36: 61)
        - "Publichnaia smertnaia kazn'," typescript (Box-folder 36: 62)
        - "Russkie v Karlsbade," holograph (Box-folder 36: 63)
        - "Vystuplinie D-ra Benesha," galley proof (Box-folder 36: 64)
        - Excerpts from untitled article, holograph (Box-folder 36: 65)
      - Vasil'eva, Olga P., translation of an article in Neue Preussische (Kreuz-) Zeitung (Berlin), no. 272, "Krizis bol'shevizma - chto proiskhodit v strane sovetov," holograph, 1927 June 12 (Box-folder 36: 66)
      - Vepen (V. P. Nikol'skii), typescript
        - "Kommunisticheskaia molodezh za robotoi" (Box-folder 36: 67)
        - "Odna iz stranits krasnogo flota" (Box-folder 36: 68)
      - Viaz'mitinov, V., "Rossiiskii zarubezhnyi s'ezd - moe zakliuchitel'noe slovo," holograph (Box-folder 36: 69)
      - Vinnichuk, "Kto fakticheski orangizoval ubiistvo 'Voikova-Voikisa'," holograph (Box-folder 36: 70)
      - Vishnevskii, A. A., "Ukrainskoe dvizhenie," typescript (Box-folder 36: 71)
      - Volgin, "Vsemirnaia tserkov Vodoleia," holograph (Box-folder 36: 72)
      - Volkobrun, S., "20 let nazad," holograph (Box-folder 36: 73)
      - Volkonskii, A. M., holograph
        - "Goneniia na katolokov v SSSR" (Box-folder 36: 74)
        - "Otkaz i vykup - o zemel'nom voprose" (Box-folder 36: 75)
      - "Vox," "Siluety-Stolypin," holograph, undated (Box-folder 36: 76)
      - Vrangel', Baron P., Easter greetings (Box-folder 36: 77)
      - Vvedenskii, Vasilii A., untitled article, typescript (Box-folder 36: 78)
      - Vygodskii, Iu., "Pis'ma i otkliki chitatelia - o neobkhodimosti ob'edineniia," holograph (Box-folder 36: 79)
      - W., "Rossiia i Pol'sha," typescript (Box-folder 36: 80)
      - Z., "Korrespondentsiia iz Belgrada," holograph (Box-folder 36: 81)
      - Zaitsev, K., untitled writings, holograph (Box-folder 36: 82)
      - Zander, L. A., "Novaia shkola," typescript (Box-folder 37: 1)
      - Zavadskii, V., "Russkie v Bessarabii," holograph (Box-folder 37: 2)
      - Zhenitskiik, N., "Cum tacet - clamant," typescript (Box-folder 37: 3)
      - Zhevakhov, N., "Invalidnyi vopros," holograph (Box-folder 37: 4)
      - Zhitkov, D. N., holograph
        - "Logika bol'shevistskogo khozianichan'ia" (Box-folder 37: 5)
        - "Otets Patrik Bell (1799-1869)" (Box-folder 37: 6)
      - Zhorzh, "Nemetskaia uchitel'skaia delegatsiia v SSSR - lichnye vpechatleniia," holograph (Box-folder 37: 7)
  - Rossiia i Slavianstvo, 1929-1932
    - Correspondence, general, 1929-1932 (Box-folder 37: 8)
    - Minutes of meetings, handwritten and typescript copies, 1932 (Box-folder 37: 9)
    - Articles submitted for publication, holograph and typescript, 1929-1930 (Box-folder 37: 10)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1890-1976 (Boxes 37-40)
  Correspondence, notes, memoranda, reports, and miscellaneous printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Writings
    - Kefeli, Dr., "Superkapitalizm ili sotsial-kapitalizm?," typescript, 1936 (Box-folder 37: 11)
    - Kon, S.S., "Methodologische Grundfragen der mathematischen und empirisch-statistischen Preis-theorie," typescript, undated (Box-folder 37: 12)
    - Nol'de, Baron, B. E., Iurii Samarin i ego vremia, 1926 (Box-folder 37: 13)
    - Schebek, A., "Memorandum," typescript copy, 1928 (Box-folder 37: 14)
  - Bratstvo Sv. Sofii--premudrosti bozhieii, statutes and membership list, typescript, 1923 (Box-folder 37: 15)
  - Chetvertyi S"ezd Russkikh Akademicheskikh Organizatsii Zagranitsei v Belgrade, pamphlet, 1928 (Box-folder 37: 16)
  - Czechoslovakia, printed matter
    - "Activite de la III International en Tchecoslovaquie,", undated (Box-folder 37: 17)
    - "Le depute Dr. Ant. Hajn contre le reconnaissance de jure du gouvernment des Soviets,", 1926 (Box-folder 37: 18)
    - "Rapport du Centre Tchechoslovaque,", undated (Box-folder 37: 19)
  - Ekonomicheskoe soveshchanie R. T. P. i F., Paris, 1928 (Box-folder 37: 20)
    Includes schedules, summaries of lectures and notes of P.B. Struve, typescript, and holograph.
  - Institut International de Cooperation Intellectuelle
    - Correspondence, including Julien Luchaire and I. Efremov, 1925-1927 (Box-folder 37: 21)
    - Reports and communiques, typescript and printed matter, 1926-1928 (Box-folder 37: 22)
  - International Anti-Bolshevik Review, printed copy, 1926 February (Box-folder 37: 23)
  - Izvestiia Rossiiskoi Akademii Nauk, printed copy, 1917 (Box-folder 37: 24)
  - Konferencja Historykow Panstw Wschodnoi Europy i Slowianszcyzny, Warsaw, 1927 (Box-folder 37: 25)
    Includes printed matter and correspondence.
  - Liga Russkoi Kul'tury
    - Statutes and membership list, printed copy in Russkaia Svoboda, 1917 (Box-folder 37: 26)
    - Struve, P. B., "Liga russkoi kul'tury," Russkaia Svoboda, printed copy, 1917 (Box-folder 37: 27)
  - Mezhdunarodnaia Antibol'shevistskaia Liga, "Ot russkago tsentra M.A.L.," typescript, undated (Box-folder 37: 28)
  - Nashe Budushchee, printed copy, 1926 June (Box-folder 37: 29)
  - Rossiiskii Zarubezhnyi S"ezd, Paris (1926)
    - Correspondence
      - Vozrozhdenie, letters re conference sent to editorial board, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 37: 30)
      - Anonymous, signed with pseudonym or initials, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 37: 31)
      - Aleksinskii, I. P., undated (Box-folder 37: 32)
      - Auerbakh, V. A., 1925 (Box-folder 37: 33)
      - Borzenskii, P., 1926 (Box-folder 37: 34)
      - Chebyshev, N. N., 1926 (Box-folder 37: 35)
      - Chelishchev, Viktor N., 1925 (Box-folder 37: 36)
      - Crout, George, 1926 (Box-folder 37: 37)
      - Denisov, Petr, undated (Box-folder 37: 38)
      - Dolinskii, N. V., undated (Box-folder 37: 39)
      - Engel'gardt, P., 1925 (Box-folder 37: 40)
      - Fedorov, Mikhail M., 1925-1926 (Box-folder 37: 41)
      - Gazanova, E., 1926 (Box-folder 37: 42)
      - Grigorovich-Barskii, Petr K., 1926 (Box-folder 37: 43)
      - Gulevich, A., 1925 (Box-folder 37: 44)
      - Gusev, V., 1925 (Box-folder 37: 45)
      - Ipat'ev, Nikolai V., 1925 (Box-folder 37: 46)
      - Ioses, Harry, 1926 (Box-folder 37: 47)
      - Kartashev, A. V., 1926 (Box-folder 37: 48)
      - Khinin, Boria V., 1925 (Box-folder 37: 49)
      - Koptev, P., undated (Box-folder 37: 50)
      - Koval', K., 1925 (Box-folder 37: 51)
      - Kovalevskii, E. P., 1926 (Box-folder 37: 52)
      - Kozyntsova, Elena, 1926 (Box-folder 37: 53)
      - Krakovskii, V., 1926 (Box-folder 37: 54)
      - Krasnov, P. N., 1926 (Box-folder 37: 55)
      - Kristi, N., 1926 (Box-folder 37: 56)
      - Krupenskii, A. N., 1926 (Box-folder 37: 57)
      - Kulaev, I. V., 1926 (Box-folder 38: 1)
      - Kutepov, Gen. A. P., 1925-1926 (Box-folder 38: 2)
      - Kuz'min, M., 1926 (Box-folder 38: 3)
      - Lukomskii, Gen. A., 1926 (Box-folder 38: 4)
      - L'vov, N. N., 1926 (Box-folder 38: 5)
      - Madzhunskii, Nikolai S., 1926 (Box-folder 38: 6)
      - Maklakov, Vasilii A., undated (Box-folder 38: 7)
      - Markozov, Vladimir, 1926 (Box-folder 38: 8)
      - Neander, Boris, 1926 (Box-folder 38: 9)
      - Novikov, Viacheslav N., 1926 (Box-folder 38: 10)
      - Obolenskii, N. L., 1925 (Box-folder 38: 11)
      - Paleolog, S., 1926 (Box-folder 38: 12)
      - Pechkovskii, Mikhail, 1925 (Box-folder 38: 13)
      - Perovskii (?), undated (Box-folder 38: 14)
      - Piltz, M. A., 1926 (Box-folder 38: 15)
      - Popov, A., 1926 (Box-folder 38: 16)
      - Pukhliakov, V., 1926 (Box-folder 38: 17)
      - Rep'ev, N. N., 1925-1926 (Box-folder 38: 18)
      - Rode, V. P., undated (Box-folder 38: 19)
      - Romano, A., 1926 (Box-folder 38: 20)
      - Rozanov, P., undated (Box-folder 38: 21)
      - Sablin, E. V., 1925 (Box-folder 38: 22)
      - Saltykov, N., 1925 (Box-folder 38: 23)
      - Savich, Ia., 1926 (Box-folder 38: 24)
      - Savich, Konstantin, 1926 (Box-folder 38: 25)
      - Semenov, Iu. F., undated (Box-folder 38: 26)
      - Sergeev, Kh. N., 1926 (Box-folder 38: 27)
      - Shebeko, N. N., 1925 (Box-folder 38: 28)
      - Sokol'skii, A., undated (Box-folder 38: 29)
      - Spektorskii, E. V., 1926 (Box-folder 38: 30)
      - Staritskii, Aleksandr, 1926 (Box-folder 38: 31)
      - Stepunin, M., 1925 (Box-folder 38: 32)
      - Tregubov, S., 1926 (Box-folder 38: 33)
      - Trepov, A. F., 1925-1926 (Box-folder 38: 34)
      - Tret'iakov, S. N., 1925 (Box-folder 38: 35)
      - Vakhtin, Iu., 1926 (Box-folder 38: 36)
      - Vasil'chikov, I. S., undated (Box-folder 38: 37)
      - Verbliunskii, A. I., 1926 (Box-folder 38: 38)
      - Voitinskii, M., 1926 (Box-folder 38: 39)
      - Voitsekhovskii, Iu. L., 1926 (Box-folder 38: 40)
      - Werner, Ragnar, 1925 (Box-folder 38: 41)
      - Zelenov, P. P., 1926 (Box-folder 38: 42)
    - Organizatsionnyi Komitet po sozyvu Rossiiskago Zarubezhnago S"ezda
      - Election
        - Election campaign leaflets and lists of candidates, printed copies, undated (Box-folder 38: 43)
        - Rules and regulations, typescript, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 38: 44)
        - Reports of miscellaneous émigré organizations re local elections; reactions and suggestions on proposals of election (Box-folder 38: 45)
      - Letter of committee to Th. Aubert, president of the Bureau de l'Entente Internationale contre la III Internationale, holograph draft, undated (Box-folder 38: 46)
      - List of participants in the congress, typescript, undated (Box-folder 38: 47)
      - Nikolai Nikolaevich, Grand Duke, question re conference's official greeting of Grand Duke, 1926 (Box-folder 38: 48)
        Includes drafts and correspondence of General A. S. Lukomskii and P. B. Struve and other material related to the Grand Duke, typescript and holograph.
      - "Proekt finansovoi Komissii," typescript, 1926 (Box-folder 38: 49)
      - "Proekt nakaza dlia Rossiiskago Zarubezhnago S"ezda,", 1925-1926 (Box-folder 38: 50)
        Includes drafts of program and other material of organizing committee, typescript.
      - Protokol zasedaniia presidiuma organizatsionnago komiteta, typescript copy, undated (Box-folder 38: 51)
      - Reports on various aspects of the Soviet regime, printed copies, 1926 (Box-folder 38: 52)
      - Resolutions and theses re agrarian question, typescript drafts, 1926 (Box-folder 38: 53)
    - Il'in, I.A., speech, typescript, 1926 (Box-folder 39: 1)
    - Minutes of closing session, typescript copy, 1926 April 11 (Box-folder 39: 2)
    - "Obrashchenie Rossiiskago Zarubezhnago S"ezda ko vsemu miru," typescript drafts and printed copy, 1926 (Box-folder 39: 3)
    - Report in French re activities and results of congress, typescript draft, undated (Box-folder 39: 4)
    - Rossiiskii Zarubezhnyi Komitet, plans and correspondence re establishment of committee, holograph and typescript, 1926 (Box-folder 39: 5)
    - Struve, P. B.
      - Interviews, drafts of reports and correspondence, holograph and typescript, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 39: 6)
      - Opening speech, typescript draft with holograph annotations, undated (Box-folder 39: 7)
    - "Tsyrkuliar Kantseliarii Ego Imperatorskago Velichestva," typescript, 1925 (Box-folder 39: 8)
    - Clippings, émigré and European press, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 39: 9-11)
    - Pencil sketches of N. E. Markov and other unidentified participant of congress [see AUDIO-VISUAL FILE], undated
  - Rossiiskoe Tsentral'noe Ob"edinenie, miscellaneous material including correspondence, membership lists and memoranda (Box-folder 39: 12)
  - Russia, Civil War (1918-1920)
    - Mogilianskii, N.M., memorandum to Maurice Paleologue, typescript, 1920 (Box-folder 39: 13)
    - Russkii-Aziatskii Bank v Yokogame, 1920 November (Box-folder 39: 14)
    - Societe des Usines de Machine Agricoles d'Aleksandrovsk, correspondence, 1920 (Box-folder 39: 15)
    - Solosoyuz Limited, miscellaneous printed matter and correspondence, 1908-1920 (Box-folder 39: 16)
    - Gen. Vrangel' and his army, 1920 (Box-folder 39: 17)
      Includes correspondence, memoranda and reports, typescript.
  - Russian émigré activities in Europe, 1924-1928
    - Advertisements for concerts and public meetings, printed copies, undated (Box-folder 39: 18)
    - Miscellaneous material, including brochures and leaflets, typescript and printed copies (Box-folder 39: 19)
    - Clippings, miscellaneous printed matter (Box-folder 39: 20)
  - Russkii Natsional'nyi Komitet, P. B. Struve, "Ot russkogo natsional'nogo komiteta," holograph and typescript copy, undated (Box-folder 40: 1)
  - Soiuz Russkikh Akademicheskikh Organizatsii za Granitsei, correspondence and memoranda, typescript, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 40: 2)
  - "Thèses de la propagande bolchévique et antithèses pour l'action de l'Entente," typescript copy, 1926 (Box-folder 40: 3)
  - Za svobodu, printed copy, 1931 July 4 (Box-folder 40: 4)
- ARKADII STRUVE FILE, 1923-1952 (Box 40)
  Personal documents and correspondence of Arkadii Struve, son of and collaborator with Petr Struve, arranged by physical form.
  - Personal documents, 1925-1949 (Box-folder 40: 5)
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1923-1950 (Box-folder 40: 6)
    - Struve, Aleksei, 1927-1950 (Box-folder 40: 7)
  - Obituaries, 1952 (Box-folder 40: 8)
- KONSTANTIN STRUVE (Hieromonk Savva) FILE, 1921-1949 (Box 40)
  Biographical material, correspondence, and writings of Konstantin Struve, son of Petr Struve, arranged by physical form.
  - Biographical material
    - Printed matter and letters about him, 1927-1949 (Box-folder 40: 9)
    - Obituaries, printed copies, 1949 (Box-folder 40: 10)
    - Church service books, printed copies, undated (Box-folder 40: 11)
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1921-1949 (Box-folder 40: 12)
    - Struve, Aleksei, Arkadii and families, 1923-1948 (Box-folder 40: 13)
  - Writings, "Vynuzhdenaia apologiia," holograph, undated (Box-folder 40: 14)
- LEV STRUVE FILE, 1923-1929 (Boxes 40-42)
  Correspondence and writings of Lev Struve, son of Petr Struve, arranged by physical form.
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1923-1928 (Box-folder 40: 15)
    - Struve, Gleb, 1923-1928 (Box-folder 40: 16)
  - Writings
    - "Oleg Brand," unpublished novel in three parts, 1926
      - Struve, Gleb, introduction to proposed publication, typescript, undated (Box-folder 40: 17)
      - Drafts, undated
        - Holograph notebooks nos. 1-13 (Box-folder 41: 1-13)
        - Holograph notebooks nos. 14-17 (Box-folder 42: 1-4)
        - Typescript copy (Box-folder 42: 5-8)
    - Miscellaneous essays, holograph, 1927 (Box-folder 42: 9-11)
  - Obituaries and letters of condolence at his death, 1929 (Box-folder 42: 12)
- NINA (ANTONINA) STRUVE FILE, 1918-1943 (Boxes 43-45)
  Personal documents, correspondence, and writings of Nina Struve, wife of Petr Struve, arranged by physical form.
  - Personal documents, 1918-1943 (Box-folder 43: 1)
  - Miscellaneous personal papers, 1926-1938 (Box-folder 43: 2)
    Includes obituary of her brother, Aleksandr Gerd.
  - Letters of condolence on the death of Nina Struve, 1943 (Box-folder 43: 3)
  - Correspondence
    - Chronological, 1920-1938 (Box-folder 43: 4)
    - Alphabetical
      - A-C, 1926-1937 (Box-folder 43: 5)
      - D-G, 1926-1931 (Box-folder 43: 6)
      - I-O, 1926-1937 (Box-folder 43: 7)
      - P-V, 1926-1937 (Box-folder 43: 8)
    - Correspondence with the Soviet Union
      - General, 1923-1928 (Box-folder 43: 9)
      - Gerd, Iuliia and Vladimir, 1920-1932 (Box-folder 43: 10)
      - Korsh, E. V., 1923-1938 (Box-folder 43: 11)
      - "Niania,", 1924-1926 (Box-folder 44: 1)
      - Zhyrmunskaia, T. N. and Iakovleva, O. A. (her mother), 1923-1927 (Box-folder 44: 2)
    - Bunina, Vera, 1926 (Box-folder 44: 3)
    - Struve, Aleksei
      - Undated fragments (Box-folder 44: 4)
      - Aleksei Struve family, including wife and children, 1926-1937 (Box-folder 44: 5)
      - 1923-1935 (Box-folder 44: 6)
      - 1936-1942 (Box-folder 44: 7)
    - Struve, Arkadii, 1926-1937 (Box-folder 44: 8)
    - Struve, Gleb, 1926-1938 (Box-folder 44: 9)
    - Struve, Iuliia, undated (Box-folder 44: 10)
    - Struve, Konstantin (Hieromonk Savva), 1924-1937 (Box-folder 45: 1)
    - Struve, Lev, 1925-1927 (Box-folder 45: 2)
    - Tyrkova-Williams, A., undated (Box-folder 45: 3)
  - Writings
    - "Peasant Life In Soviet Russia," London Times (?), printed copy, 1920 (Box-folder 45: 4)
    - Reminiscences re Revolution of 1917, holograph and handwritten copy, undated (Box-folder 45: 5)